Guide to the Office of the President records, 1795-2007 RG0002
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Scrapbooks, 1916-1965; Series 6; 37.5 Linear Feet 23 record center cartons, 4 oversize volumes
  The scrapbooks are arranged chronologically.
  This series contains scrapbooks compiled by the President's Office. The scrapbooks include information concerning inaugurations, Columbian Women, groundbreakings, commencements, Glee Club, professors, Rifle Team, alumni, drama, student union building, Phi Beta Kappa, Potomac Rose Society, the Medical School, the Law School, lectures, World War II, Dr. Walter Freeman and Dr. James Watts, St. Paul's Church, sports, Hospital Golden Book, Goat Show, Jacqueline Bouvier Kennedy Onassis, race relations, Hillel, Edward Teller, Faculty Women's Club, College Bowl, radio, television, and dance. Materials include newspaper clippings, programs, invitations, etc. These scrapbooks date from 1923-1965.
  Formerly ACC#940
  - Scrapbook pages, 1916-1929 (Box 232)
    Pages disassembled into chronologically ordered folders. Contents: tickets, programs, and invitations to lectures, dinners, convocations, commencements, inauguration of Pres. Lewis; Board of Trustees and Alumni Association ballots, constitution, meeting announcements and invitations; 1916 Army ROTC student enrollment contract; pamphlets for summer school sessions. Materials range in date from 1916-1929.
  - Scrapbook, 1923 (Box 233, Volume 1)
    Vol. I. News Headlines: Pres. Lewis election, inauguration, including address; various Pres. Lewis speeches regarding sports, GWU, education, Pres. Harding eulogy; GWU lectures; new university buildings: plans, groundbreaking ceremony; Columbian Women activities; debates with Oxford; courses to train policewomen; attack on faculty; Pres. Hodgkin's portrait; Dean Wilbur's portrait; Typothetae dinner and election; opening of school; US government workers as GW students; ad for GWU.
  - Scrapbook, 1923-1924 (Box 233, Volume 2)
    Vol. II. News Headlines: Groundbreaking ceremonies; women's rifle and fencing teams; sororities and fraternities; drama, chorus; Naval ROTC courses begin; opening of nursing school; scientific driving test between women and men; building endowment campaign; lectures; Baptist Church attempt to purchase GWU; Pres. Lewis lectures; Cambridge-GWU debate; new football coach, Harry Crum; first woman elected to Board of Trustees, Jessie Fant Evans; 1924 Commencement.
  - Scrapbook, 1925-1927 (Box 233, Volume 3)
    News Headlines: Convocations, commencements; football commercialization; faculty baseball games; sports club activities, including rifle, tennis, track, girls' basketball; sorority and fraternity activities; drama club; square and compass club; Hour Glass society; Glee Club performances; Country fair; Columbian Women scholarships; founding of Elizabeth Brown Scholarship; Stockton Hall dedication; GW Medical Center; GWU #1 Hospital; Diplomatic School established; third building plans; Pres. Lewis lectures; Urban University Meeting; Bar examinations; Honorary degree to Dr. Noyes; Oxford Debate; military courses; Inauguration of Kolbe as president of Polytechnic Institute; Judge E. Parker Elected as Board member; student marriage engagements; GWU enrollment at record highs; National Education Association meeting; evening of music at Mt. Vernon; Dean Miller speaks; Dean Miller resigns; 'The Lash' controversy; Dr. Hau commits suicide; typical American girl contest; 'Cat's Eye' controversy; Stockton portrait; Jefferson Day activities; new gym planned; Richardson to Board of Education; essay prizes; Library Alcove memorial to Dr. Swisher; Daughters of the American Revolution; discussion of national education; Columbian Women activities; women versus male drivers; Pulitzer prize.
  - Scrapbook, 1927-1929 (Box 233, Volume 4)
    News Headlines: Pres. Marvin; Elizabeth Culleen elected as Columbian Woman Head; Columbian Women scholarships; woman debaters; Masonic endowment; commencements and convocations; Prof. Doyle promoted to Dean; building plans; zoological unit moved and expanded; sports; debate; Troubadours; GWU scholarships; GW Hospital Ball; Theatre Benefit for Columbian Women; Prof. Moss; GW Hospital.
  - Scrapbook, 1929-1930 (Box 233, Volume 5)
    News Headlines: Advisor position created for foreign students; Prof. Crandall as Director of Arts; Delta Phi Epsilon becomes new fraternity; Dr. Donalson write book on economics; GWU requires aptitude tests; lectures; Alumni reunion; Alumni honors; debate team; Glee Club; opening of Junior College; British PM, MacDonald given honorary degree; Mexican Pres. Ortiz Rubio given honorary degree; Spanish teachers gather; Depew endowment; Medical Alum Banquet; sorority scholarships; school publications; Pres. Marvin lectures in Europe; Columbian Women activities; dance team; rifle team; endowment for world affairs school; athletic endowments; Mother's Day.
  - Scrapbook, 1930-1931 (Box 234, Volume 1)
    News Headlines: Convocations and commencements; Pres. Marvin speeches/lectures; new faculty; GW makes Association of American Universities' list; Virgil's birthday celebration with Italian Ambassador; Fine Arts Department expands course offerings; debates; mother's Day; Columbian Women; Kappa Alpha convention; football; Troubadours; Girls' Chorus; sorority pledges; Dean Hodgkins dies; Carr estate willed to GWU; Pan Hellenic luncheon; Alumni luncheon; Alumni honor Justices; drama club.
  - Scrapbook, 1930-1931 (Box 234, Volume 2)
    News Headlines: Girls' archery, rifle, and field hockey teams; modern languages; Student Union building; debates: with Scots, Swarthmore, women versus men; commencement and convocation; Siamese monarch given honorary degree; Pres. Marvin to visit Mexico; tree planting; Glee Club; Columbian Women activities; Alumni activities; new Dean of Medicine, Dr. McKinley; 'Talkie' pupil tests-education through films.
  - Scrapbook, 1930-1934 (Box 234, Volume 3)
    Contents: Programs, invitations etc. for commencements, convocations, reunions etc.
  - Scrapbook, 1931-1932 (Box 234, Volume 4)
    Vol. 1. Contents: Administration; Alumni; bi-centennial; Columbian Women; Constitutional Review; faculty; general; Pres. Marvin; Medical School; Medical Society; Navy Law students; opening of school; scholarships; special occasions; student activities; students; summer session; Sunday stories.
  - Scrapbook, 1932-1933 (Box 234, Volume 5)
    Vol. 2. Contents: Botany exhibit; Convocation; Dean Wilbur Day; Homecoming; lecturers; Masonic Endowment; Mother's Day; Pan American Day; Women's Activities; All University Ball; Band; Clubs; Forensics; Girl's Athletics; Glee Clubs; Pledges; The University Hatchet; students; Sunday stories.
  - Scrapbook, 1932-1933 (Box 235, Volume 1)
    Contents: Press releases regarding: Conference on Hispanic American Affairs; Conference on the Effectiveness of Unemployment relief; opening of GWU; news clippings regarding: Feiker Lectures; summer session registration; Botany Dept. field trip; Unemployment Relief Conference (DC and non-DC papers).
  - Scrapbook, 1932-1933 (Box 235, Volume 2)
    Contents: News clippings on rural schooling, Conference on Hispanic American Affairs; Dr. cooper's appointment as Prof. Education (DC and non-DC papers); summer session; Conference on Curriculum; Conference on Problems of Secondary Education; Conference on Socio-Economic Problems and their Educational Implications; GWU Forum; press releases for opening of summer session; Conference on Hispanic American Affairs; Conference on Problems of Secondary Education; Conference on Socio-Economic Problems and their Educational Implications; issue of 'School Life', June 1933.
  - Scrapbook, 1932-1933 (Box 235, Volume 3)
    Vol. 1. Contents: Administration; Alumni Organization, including general, Law, Medical, and Nursing; Columbian Women; Faculty Women; Bicentennial; Faculty; Fine Arts; General; GWU Law Review; Law School; Pres. Marvin; Medical School; School Opening; Radio Forum; Scholarships.
  - Scrapbook, 1932-1934 (Box 235, Volume 4)
    Vol. 2. News headlines: Botany exhibit; Center for Inter-American Studies; convocations; Sec. Hull given honorary doctorate; homecoming; lectures; Dr. Alfred Zimmern; Masonic Endowment Fund; Mother's Day; Pan-American Day; band; Cherry Tree; art club; Engineer's Council; sororities and fraternities; International Relations Club; Liberal Club; Luther Club; Newman Club; Student Bar Association; Symphony Club; Fiesta Club; Cue and Curtain; drama; debates; public speaking conference; Troubadours; Girls' archery, field hockey, rifle, softball, equestrian; Glee Club; Hatchet; Pan-Hellenic Association; students; fraternity house fire; summer school; Sunday stories; Trustee elections.
  - Scrapbook, 1933-1934 (Box 235, Volume 5)
    Vol. 1. Contents: Alumni Trustees; Student aid; High School Aid; Center of Inter-American Studies; Alumni Organizations, general, Law and Medical; Columbian Women; Faculty Women; Women's Board of GWU Hospital; Faculty; General; Tuberculosis Institute Meeting; Law Review; Pres. Marvin; Medical School and Hospital; School opening; Radio Forum; Scholarships.
  - Scrapbook, 1935-1936 (Box 236, Volume 1)
    Contents: Prof. Cox; Social Science Hall; Prof. Harrick; Pres. Marvin heads scientific group; Pupil character work; Compton, Hansen, Stenenson; Dr. Marvin; school opening; peace movement; Mrs. J. F. Evans; February registration; W.J. Flather dies; Dean Ruedriger appointed as GW president; building repairs and plans; future Vets seek bonus bill; Alumni Organizations, including faculty, Columbian Women, GW Hospital Women's board; Cruse and TV; safety campaign; graduation; homecoming; press meeting; Dr. Kotz honored; Dr, McKinley honored; childbirth drug; Dr. Cadman Convocation speaker; Medical post-graduate clinic; Graduation sermon by Philips; AT&T officers; school publications; Student Congress, Hatchet Editor quits; Cue and Curtain; Cherry Tree Contest; Inter fraternity Prom; Pan Hellenic Prom; Chorus and Orchestra; Dr. Kindler; Glee Club; Fiesta Club; students; summer session; Sunday stories.
  - Scrapbook, 1937-1938 (Box 236, Volume 2)
    Contents: Radio workshop; appointment of john Busick; faculty regulations; journalism course expansion; Athletic field; Phi Beta Kappa; new Major plan; Mrs. Joshua Evans; Hall of Government; Posture pictures; Robert V. Fleming; Mrs. Lilian Wright Smith; T. W. Noyes birthday banquet; students attack Rule 6; death of Mrs. Wilbur; GW memorial fund; Coach Pixlee's sabbatical leave; Dr. Overholder joins faculty; purchase of land; University calendar altered; death of Abram Lisner; library science school; Waldron Faulkner; G.H.A.; new Medical School; peace strike; radio station; Caroline E. Orth; Trustee election; faculty promotions; scholarships; Alumni Organizations, including Faculty Women, Columbian Women, GW Hospital Women's Fund; faculty; general; homecoming; Pres. Marvin; opening of school; Law Review; Aptitude tests for nurses; prenatal clinic; Prof. Deibert's teas; lectures by Dr. Kose; Davis speaking contest; P.T.A. Institute; Armistice Day Services; Smith-Reed-Russell Medical Society; Australian debaters; Theobald Smith Medal Award; Conference for Senior High School Students' International debate; Dr. C.G. Heyd lecture; Medical Clinic; Phi-Beta Kappa installation and elections; convocation; Mortar Board installation; Rose Institute; Inter-American Conference; Prof. Laski's lectures; Verse Speaking Choir; Law Banquet; Dance symposium; Washington Conference on Theoretical Physics; Ophthalmology course; Home Economics luncheon; Wild Flower Show; Laying of Cornerstone of Hall of Government; Potomac Rose Society; Prof. Schmidt retirement; commencement; dinner of the Order of Golf; Union elections; rushing; Pledge Day; Buff and Blue Room; Anti-Syphilis campaign; Inter-Collegiate newspaper association; Cue and Curtain; Glee Club; Freshman Club forum; Inter-fraternity prom; rifle team; orchesis; Panhellenic Prom; Student Council elections; Freshman Congress; May Day (Mortar Board Tapping); Cherry Tree Beauty Tree; students; summer school; Sunday stories.
  - Scrapbook, 1938-1939 (Box 236, Volume 3)
    Contents: GW Memorial fund; Dr. Bloedorn appointment; Lisner library building; return of Jim Pixlee; appointment of Maw Ferrington; G.H.A.; American Medical Association; appointment of Wilson and Brookes; athletes dismissed; appointment of Dr. Bolwell; Gallinger Hospital; law graduates and US jobs; Hatchet editor fired; scholarships; Alumni Organizations, including faculty Women, Columbia Women, GW Hospital Women's Board; faculty; general, Pres. Marvin; opening of school; opening of Hall of Government; Parent-Teacher Service Unit; Mary K. Browne tennis exhibition; Dr. Gamow lecture; Sweetheart contest; Inter-American Center Conference; Davis Speaking Contest; Phi Beta Kappa initiates; public speaking contest; physicist meeting; Law Conference; Model Senate; GW Clinic; convocation; Smith-Reed-Russell lecture; modern dance recital; G Street Follies; Eye Specialist Conference; Mortar Board; commencement; Law Review; Newman Club Convention; rushing; Student Congress elected; pledge day; Mortar Board luncheon; GW Women's athletics; Inter-Collegiate Newspaper association; Nassau Debaters; Phi Lambda Delta initiation; rifle team; Panhellenic Conference; GW Physical Education Feature night; Engineer's Ball; Washington Dance association; Beauty Contest; Inter fraternity Prom; Panhellenic Prom; student elections; Panhellenic Interfraternity Sing; students; summer school; Sunday stories.
  - Scrapbook, 1939-1940 (Box 237, Volume 1)
    Contents: GW Hospital on approved list; new library; CAA classes; Mrs. Dimock's bequest; athletes take up square dancing; Dean Feiker's appointment; S.J.D. degree established; School of Pharmacy accredited; Comptroller Holmes dies; Miss Gibbon resigns; Homer S. Cummings gives clinic to GW; Wilbur J. Carr-Board elections; scholarships awarded to High Schools; Mrs. Chauncey Depew's bequest; Columbian Women scholarship fund; Dr., Stirling's trip to Mexico; Alumni Stag party; Alumni Association elections; Mrs. Marvin head of hospital board; croissant's simplification of words; Dean Doyle-Languages and War; Dean Johnstone's trip to China; Dean Lapham's death; Dr. Howard F. Kane; Dean Kayser's radio talks on war.
  - Scrapbook, 1940-1941 (Box 237, Volume 2)
    News headlines: New education courses; commencement; scholarships; Lisner Auditorium; Mrs. Depew's endowment; defense engineer courses; rifle team; tennis club; James Pixlee; football team; Columbian Women; Mortar Board; faculty additions; paternity testing; Dean Acheson; vitamins; nurse commencement; WW II; Pharmacy School expands laboratory; building of Fleming Auditorium; homecoming; Medical Society; fraternity and sorority activities; debates; young and old women in the workplace; Japanese trade threat in Latin America; aviation medicine; beauty queen contest; Glee Clubs; Law lectures; 25-year faculty honored; Ophthalmology courses; modern dance; Student Council dance.
  - Scrapbook, 1941-1942 (Box 237, Volume 3)
    Contents: Defense Training Courses; District Hospital Plan; Victory Book Campaign; aviation course for teachers; Law School cuts entry standards; sketch of Corcoran hall; War Service projects; Garnett and Bliven named Deans; six new courses in War training; William Reinhart resigns; summer sessions; Columbian Women; Mary Agnes Brown; Phi Beta Phi Alumnae; Freeman talks to GW Medical Society; Alumni honor 25-year teachers; faculty promotions/military leaves; faculty deaths; Brain operations-Drs. Freeman and Watt; Dean Doyle speaks in Knoxville; pharmacy and the Civilian Defense Program/Dean Briggs; dean and faculty lectures; Psychosurgery: book by Drs. Freeman, Watt, and Hunt; Pres. Marvin speeches; Law Review; school opening; Homecoming; lecture series; debates; summer school; students in the news; rushing; pledging; Cue and Curtain; Cherry Tree editors; Camera Club; Rifle Team; Glee Club; Mortar Board.
  - Publicity Survey, 1942-1943 (Box 237, Volume 4)
    Contents: List of GWU articles and advertisements in local newspapers
  - Scrapbook, 1942-1943 (Box 238, Volume 1)
    Contents: School opening; new faculty; Lisner Auditorium; new courses; wartime courses at GW; Hispanic American courses; women-only engineering course; pledging; scholarships; Columbian Women; sororities and fraternities; faculty in the news; Pres. Marvin; debates; Panhellenic society; commencement; students in the news; Thespians; dance; debate; Glee Club.
  - Scrapbook, 1944-1946 (Box 238, Volume 2)
    Contents: Glee Club; advertisements; invitations and programs for commencements, lectures, and convocations; demolition of St. Paul's church; veterans at GW.
  - Scrapbook, 1945-1946 (Box 238, Volume 3)
    Contents: Alumni, Trustees; Arts and Religion Departments; Atomic-Rocket-Ballistics Laboratories; Commencement; dance, drama, Glee Club, Lisner Auditorium; School of Education; endowments; faculty; fraternities and sororities; parking garage; textbook shortage; School of Government; History and Geography departments; individual faculty and students; School of Journalism; Law School; Medical School; participation in national and local affairs; registration; special courses in aviation, department store, Red Cross, summer, and sex; sports, including basketball, football, track, and women's sports; student activities and clubs; scholarships.
  - Scrapbook, 1939-1942 (Box 238, Volume 4)
    Contents: Invitations to lectures; commencement and convocation programs.
  - Scrapbook, 1945-1948 (Box 239, Volume 1)
    Contents: Invitations, programs, guides to convocation, commencement, lectures, and other school events; Alumni Reviews; historical booklets; class bulletins; map of GW and environs.
  - Scrapbook, 09/01/1946-09/01/1947 (Box 239, Volume 2)
    Vol. 2. Contents: Advertisements; alumni; American Youth for Democracy; art; atom studies; band; cheer leaders; Columbian Women; Cue and Curtain; dance; education; endowments; scholarships; faculty; fashion; fraternity and sorority; Glee Club; Student government; Hatchet; homecoming; home economics; GW Hospital; journalism; Law Department; Local High School Alumni; Pres. Marvin; May Queen; parking; pharmacy; photography; physical education; radio; religion; sailing club; segregation; social activities; speech club; sports; Student Council; students in the news; textbooks; Veteran students.
  - Scrapbook, 1946-1947 (Box 239, Volume 3)
    Contents: Advertisements; alumni; trustees; American Civilization course; arts; religion; atomic research; building service employees; commencement; drama; economics; endowments; engineering; faculty appointments, sabbaticals; foreign service courses; honorary degrees; language; Law school; Medical school; new buildings; Univ. publications; registration; tuition; Russian courses; segregation; special courses; speech clinic; student veterans; military officers; part time students.
  - Scrapbook, 1946-1947 (Box 239, Volume 4)
    Contents: Lisner Auditorium: advertisements, Ballet for America, Clare Tree Major, Columbia Light Opera Company, Cue and Curtain, various performers, National Symphony; Sports: baseball, basketball, football, golf, rifle team, sailing, swimming, tennis, track.
  - Scrapbook, 1947-1948 (Box 240, Volume 1)
    Vol. 1. Contents: Advertisements; band; Chemistry Department; Classical Language and Literature Department; commencement; Dance Department; Drama Department; Economics Department; Education Department; Engineering Department; English Department; faculty; Faculty Women's Club; Foreign Service Department; fraternities; Geography Department; High School Discussion Conferences; History Department; 'History of GW'; homecoming; Home Economics Department; Hospital; International House; journalism; Lisner Auditorium; Law School; Medical School: convocation, faculty, Medical Society, orientation; Mortar Board; Navy courses; Panhellenic organization; Parent-Teacher's Institute; peeping Tom epidemic; Pharmacy Department; Philosophy Department; Physical Education Department; Physics Department; Placement Office; public relations; radio; real estate courses; registration and admissions; Religion Department; Science Department; scientific management courses; secretarial studies; service employees; sororities; Speech Department; sports; street parking; Student Union building; trustees; University Women's Recreation Association; Veteran Students; Victory Council; Welling Hall; West End Association.
  - Scrapbook, 1947-1948 (Box 240, Volume 2)
    Vol. 2. Contents: Advertisements; Alumni Association; alumni; commencement; Cue and Curtain; Current Affairs Club; Debate Team; Engineering Department; faculty; fraternities and sororities; Glee Club and Band; Hatchet; Cherry Tree; Surveyor; High School activities; homecoming; Home Economics; honorary organizations; GW Hospital; independent organizations; Journalism Department; Law School; Lisner Auditorium; May Queen; Cloyd Heck Marvin; Medical School; parking; Pharmacy Department; psychology; radio; registration; religion; scholarships; service employees; science; social activities; speech; sports; students; student activities off campus; Student Council; Student Faculty Committee; the Trumans; Veteran Students; Veterans Club; Who's Who; Women's Recreation Association; World Youth.
  - Scrapbook, 1947-1948 (Box 240, Volume 3)
    Vol. 3. Contents: Advertisements; basketball; football; beanies; tickets; television; student support; Touchdown Club; Sailing club; Alumni Association; Colonials Inc.; Colonials Program Series; Columbian Women; commencement; Faculty members honored after 25 years of service; Faculty Women's Club; homecoming; honorary and social fraternities and sororities; Lido club honors Italian-American GW grads; Medical School (alumni societies).
  - Scrapbook, undated (Box 241, Volume 1)
    Contents: 'Summer School Record' newspaper; bulletins/schedule of classes; orientation programs; football and basketball booklets, including 'Meet the Colonials'; drama programs; invitations and programs for convocation and commencement; faculty directories; Glee Club; sorority booklets; application for admission; Alumni dinner.
  - Scrapbook, 1948-1949 (Box 241, Volume 2)
    Vol. 1. Contents: Sororities and fraternities; American Educational Theater Association; American Society of Engineers; American Society of Mechanical Engineers; Auditorium events; campus scenes; chapel; Columbian House; convocation; counseling center; dance; debates; dormitories; School of Education; faculty; faculty follies; Faculty Women's Club; fellowships; flirting; Foreign Service Review Course; Geography department; Glee Club; Hall of Government; General Grant; Katherine Hall; Hatchet; Hillel; Hospital activities; Inaugural parade float; inaugural tea; journalism essay award; law School; library; Cloyd Marvin; School of Medicine; Medical Society; Naval officers' certificates; Parent-Teacher Institute; School of Pharmacy; Department of Physical Education; GWU Players; Reading Clinic; real estate courses; Religion Department; registration; scholarships; Speech Department; Summer term; Victory Council; vivisection; Washington Counseling Center; Wesleyan Foundation.
  - Scrapbook, 1948-1949 (Box 241, Volume 3)